<resources xmlns:tools="http://schemas.android.com/tools">
    <string name="app_name">Bangladesh University</string>
    <string name="title_activity_dash_board">DashBoard</string>
    <string name="title_home">Home</string>
    <string name="title_faculties">Faculties</string>
    <string name="title_more">More</string>

    <!--    about section-->
    <string name="info_about_bu">About BU</string>
    <string name="info_misson_vision">Mission &amp; Vision</string>

    <!--    Academic section-->
    <string name="info_offered_degree">Offered Degree</string>
    <string name="info_rules_regulation">Rules &amp; Regulation</string>
    <string name="info_academic_policies">Academic Policies</string>

    <!--    Admission section-->
    <string name="info_admission">Admission Requirements</string>

    <!--    administration section-->
    <string name="info_message_from_founder">Message Form Founder</string>
    <string name="info_board_of_trust">Board Of Trust</string>
    <string name="info_vc_office">VC Office</string>

    <!--    Office Info section-->
    <string name="info_registrar_office">Registrar</string>
    <string name="info_controller_office">Controller</string>
    <string name="info_office_of_the_account">Account</string>
    <string name="info_library_office">Library</string>
    <string name="info_it_office">IT</string>

    <!--    Collaboration section-->
    <string name="info_stamford_university">Stamford</string>


    <!--    about bu-->
    <string name="about_bu_part_1">Bangladesh University (BU) was established in 2001 under Private University Act, 1992 by Mr. Quazi Azher Ali, as a non-profit, non-political private university pioneering in computer-based education. It has been accredited by the Government of the People’s Republic of Bangladesh. Its curricula as well as programs have been approved by the University Grants Commission (UGC) of Bangladesh. BU is approved by the Government of Bangladesh for awarding degrees in various disciplines. We are committed to excellence and innovation in pursuing applied knowledge through research and creative activities with the objectives of producing world-class professionals responsive to the need of the Bangladeshi community and world at large.</string>
    <string name="about_bu_part_2">BU started its academic session with 17 students and 0.02 acres of space in 2001. Now BU accommodates more than 6500 students in four campuses. With 130 full-time and 30 part-time faculty members and 110 administrative members, our community continues to grow to cater to the needs of both the students the nation as well.</string>
    <string name="about_bu_part_3">The first campus of BU is located at a posh area of the capital city near the Bangladesh Parliament at 15/1, Iqbal Road, Mohammadpur, Dhaka-1207. Other two campuses are also in Mohammadpur. The permanent campus having 1.7026 acres of land is located at 5/B, Beribandh Main Road, Adabar, Mohammadpur, Dhaka which is well connected with other parts of Dhaka city and only one and a half kilometers away from the first campus. The permanent campus has already been inaugurated by Advocate Jahangir Kabir Nanak, MP and former Hon’ble State Minister for Local Govt., Rural Development and Co-operatives on October 18, 2011.</string>
    <string name="about_bu_part_4">The President of the People’s Republic of Bangladesh is the Chancellor of Bangladesh University (BU). He appointed Quazi Azher Ali, M.Sc. (DU), MPA (Harvard), the founder of BU as its Vice Chancellor. Virtually BU is the vivid imaginative conception of this noble soul. He held this position since its inception in October, 2001 till the day of his death on December 15, 2009. He had high academic achievement with long and varied experiences in national and international administration including Secretary to the Government of Bangladesh and Executive Director of Asian Development Bank (ADB). Mr. Ali agreed to accept taka one per month as salary considering the initial financial problems for a new noncommercial institution.</string>

    <!--  Mission and Vision-->
    <string name="vision">The vision of BU is to develop and nurture talent with modern knowledge to meet the national needs in global perspective. To ensure a knowledge-based society and to meet the challenges of 21st century, it extends its focus on high standard quality education, innovation, discovery, research and creative activities. Thus it will be able to generate capable and ethical leaders who will lead the nation and the globe as well. BU is committed to reflecting the values and aspirations of the nation.</string>
    <string name="mission">The primary mission of BU is to ensure quality higher education at a minimum cost especially for the financially backward group of people. It is keen to expand information technology to help build up a digital Bangladesh. Through co-curricular activities, combining knowledge and training along with ethical values, it wants to create a patriotic community that will feel the urge within to serve the nation and the humanity. Our mission is to create future leaders that can contribute to change the nation for better tomorrow.</string>

    <!-- Offered Degree-->
    <string name="od_title">Bangladesh University (BU) currently operates 15 programs under three distinct faculties</string>

    <string name="od_faculty_FSET">1. Faculty of Science, Engineering &amp; Technology</string>
    <string name="od_faculty_FASSL">2. Faculty of Arts, Social Science &amp; Law</string>
    <string name="od_faculty_FBAE">3. Faculty of Business Administration &amp; Economics</string>

    <string name="od_under_gra_are_option_title">Faculty of Science, Engineering &amp; Technology</string>
    <string name="od_under_gra_are_option">Undergraduate Programs are:</string>
    <string name="od_under_gra_bsc">Bachelor of Science (B.Sc.), Honors in - </string>
    <string name="od_under_gra_cse">1. Computer Science &amp; Engineering (CSE)</string>
    <string name="od_under_gra_math">2. Mathematics</string>
    <string name="od_under_gra_phar">5. Pharmacy</string>
    <string name="od_under_gra_eee">4. Electrical and Electronic Engineering (EEE)</string>
    <string name="od_under_gra_arch">3. Architecture (BArch) [5 years]</string>

    <string name="od_fassl_title">Faculty of Arts, Social Science &amp; Law (FASSL)</string>
    <string name="od_fassl_title_options">Bachelor of Arts (BA), Honors in -</string>
    <string name="od_fassl_english">1. English</string>
    <string name="od_fassl_sociology">2. Sociology</string>
    <string name="od_fassl_llb">3. Bachelor of Laws (LL.B)</string>
    <string name="od_gra_master_prog_are">Graduate (Master) Programs are:</string>
    <string name="od_ma_english_1">3. MA in English - One year</string>
    <string name="od_ma_english_2">4. MA in English - Two years</string>
    <string name="od_ma_llb_1">1. Master of Laws (LL.M) - One year</string>
    <string name="od_ma_llb_2">2. Master of Laws (LL.M) - Two years</string>

    <string name="od_FBAE_title">Faculty of Business Administration &amp; Economics (FBAE)</string>
    <string name="od_BBA_major_in">* Bachelor of Business Administration (BBA), Major in -</string>
    <string name="od_bba_account">1. Accounting</string>
    <string name="od_bba_finanace">2. Finance</string>
    <string name="od_bba_market">3. Marketing</string>
    <string name="od_bba_hrm">4.HRM</string>
    <string name="od_bba_economics">* Bachelor of Economics</string>
    <string name="od_mba_regular">1. Master of Business Administration (MBA) - Regular</string>
    <string name="od_mba_executive">2. Master of Business Administration (MBA) - Executive</string>
    <string name="od_mba_bba_holder">3. Master of Business Administration (MBA) - BBA Holder</string>

    <!--    Academic Policies-->
    <string name="ap_one">Class and Examination Schedules are specified in Academic Calendar of the university. Information about year and semester wise course distribution has been included in the respective section of this catalog and also available in the university website.</string>
    <string name="lessonPlan_one">Lesson Plan</string>
    <string name="lessonPlan_two">At the beginning of the semester, each faculty member will submit a lesson plan with statement of the program of evaluation of students’ performance by way of essays, tests examination, seminar presentations along with the relative weight of these methods in relation to the overall grade and the timing of each major evaluation.</string>
    <string name="attendence_one">Class Attendance</string>
    <string name="attendence_two">The students are required to attend at least 70% of the classes held in each course in a semester. Failing which they will not be allowed to sit for the Semester Final Examination. However, the authority may condone the shortage of requisite percentage on grounds acceptable to the authority.</string>
    <string name="Coding_system_in_Final_Examination_one">Coding system in Final Examination</string>
    <string name="Coding_system_in_Final_Examination_two">In order to attain transparency Final Examinations are conducted on the basis of coding system. In this system answer scripts are coded so that no examiners will be able to identify any student. Moreover, all answer scripts are evaluated in the university premises within a stipulated time and results are uploaded on the software immediately after the evaluation of answer scripts to publish results in a shortest possible time. And thereby transcripts and certificates be issued to the outgoing students without any delay.</string>
    <string name="Credit_Hours_System_one">Credit Hours System</string>
    <string name="Credit_Hours_System_two">The academic system of study of BU is based on credit hours. Three credit hours theory course represents two lecture per week per semester. Duration of each class is of one and half hours. Two credit hours theory course represents one lecture per week per semester. The duration of each class is of one and half hours. One 1.5 credit hours lab course represents one lab class per week per semester. Duration of each lab class will be of three hours. Credits are also assigned to project/thesis work taken by students. The amount of credits assigned to such work may vary from discipline to discipline.</string>
    <string name="Mid_term_and_Final_Examinations_one">Mid term and Final Examinations</string>
    <string name="Mid_term_and_Final_Examinations_two">The university has a high ethical standard and concerted efforts made to conduct all examinations by fair means.  20% of marks is allotted for continuous assessment, 30% of marks is allotted for Midterm Examination and remainder 50% of marks is allotted for Final Examination. Midterm Examination of one and half hour duration is conducted by individual department and Final Examination of two hour duration is conducted centrally by Controller of Examinations .The students are evaluated by their teachers, especially when they give tests, quizzes and tutorials during the class hour. Conducting Mid-term Examination and Final Examination is a collective enterprise.</string>
    <string name="Makeup_Missed_Failed_Examinations_one">Makeup (Missed/Failed) Examinations</string>
    <string name="Makeup_Missed_Failed_Examinations_two">A student who has failed to set for either Mid-Term or Semester Final Examination or both for serious illness or death or accident in the family or other valid reasons may submit an application to the Head of the Department for Makeup/Retake Examination. This application must be supported by valid documentary proof. A student has to apply to the Controller of Examinations on prescribed form through concerned Head of the Department paying prescribed fees as determined by the competent authority.</string>
    <string name="Improvement_Examination_one">Improvement Examination(s)</string>
    <string name="Improvement_Examination_two">Student(s) obtaining C+ and below grade in any course(s) are eligible to sit for Improvement Examination. The concerned student(s) will have to re-register the course(s) and sit for the said examination(s) with the next batch on payment of improvement fees. However, for Lab/ Practical/ Sessional courses/Viva-voce, no Improvement Examination(s) will be entertained.</string>
    <string name="Dropout_Course_due_to_disciplinary_action_Recourse_Examinations_one">Dropout Course(s) [due to disciplinary action]/ Recourse(s) Examinations</string>
    <string name="Dropout_Course_due_to_disciplinary_action_Recourse_Examinations_two">For dropout (due to disciplinary action) course(s), a student shall have to re-registrar &amp; re-course the dropout course(s) and attend the classes accordingly and will sit for the examination(s) with the next batch paying re-course examination fee(s) for the course(s).</string>
    <string name="grading_one">Grading System</string>
    <string name="grading_two">The final course grade is being prepared based on an overall evaluation of a student’s performance in assignments, examinations, quizzes, case works, term papers, laboratory tests and class attendance. Each course teacher determines the grade of the student concerned.</string>
    <!--  Admission -->
    <string name="addmission_start">BU Admissions at a Glance</string>
    <string name="student_enrollment_title">Student Enrollment</string>
    <string name="student_enrollment_title_one">Undergraduates: 6000</string>
    <string name="student_enrollment_title_two">Graduates: 500</string>
    <string name="under_graduation_admission_one">Undergraduate admission</string>
    <string name="under_graduation_admission_two">10 departments and programs offer graduate study</string>
    <string name="under_graduation_admission_three">Application deadlines vary by program</string>
    <string name="graduation_admission_one">Graduate admission</string>
    <string name="graduation_admission_two">3 departments and programs offer graduate study.</string>
    <string name="graduation_admission_three">Application deadlines vary by program.</string>
    <string name="financial_aid_one">Financial Aid</string>
    <string name="financial_aid_two">20% - 100% weaver policy for merit students.</string>
    <string name="financial_aid_three">Graduate study aid is based on availability of funds and academic merit.</string>
    <string name="financial_aid_four">About 3% of graduate students receive financial aid.</string>
    <string name="repeatCourse">Repeating Courses</string>
    <string name="repeatCourseTwo">If a student fails to get a passing grade in a course, he/she will be awarded an ‘F’ grade and will have to repeat the course on payment of fees. The student must re-take a failing course when offered after paying the necessary fees and must also successfully complete the course. The grade earned on the retake will be shown in the transcript along with ‘F’ grade earned in the first time the course was taken. But the grade earned on the course (s) repeated will be substituted for “F” in computing CGPA. A course can be retaken only once. Improvement of course grade will only be allowed to students with C, D or F after payment of prescribed fees.</string>

    <string name="academicStand">Academic Standing</string>
    <string name="academicStandTwo">For graduate program, a student must maintain a minimum CGPA of 2.25 to remain in good standing. Student of under-graduate program with CGPA between 1 and 2 after the first two semesters will be placed on probation for the next two semesters. If students placed on probation fail to raise their CGPA to at least 2, after the probation period they will face dismissal from the course. If a student’s CGPA falls below 2, he/she will again be placed on probation.</string>
    <string name="onlineResult1">Online Result</string>
    <string name="onlineResult2">Online Results are generated by the departments concerned in the Student Management System from where every registered student can observe his/her result/progress soon after the conclusion of each semester.</string>
    <string name="transcript1">Transcript</string>
    <string name="transcript2">Transcripts covering result(s) of one/more than one semester or of all semesters studied and completed by a student may be supplied to a student on his/her demand on payment of predetermined fee(s). Each transcript shall bear the embossed Bangladesh University Monogram.</string>
    <string name="provesional1">Provisional/Original Certificate </string>
    <string name="provesional2">A student having completed all his/her courses as well as duration of his assigned program shall be entitled to have his/her Provisional/Original Certificate as the case may be on payment of predetermined fee(s). No student shall be issued Provisional/Original Certificate unless he/she completes the required duration of the program.</string>
    <string name="appAgiPun1">Appeal against punishment</string>
    <string name="appAgiPun2">If a student is aggrieved by an order of punishment awarded by the authority as per decision of the Disciplinary Committee, he/she may file an appeal before the Vice Chancellor within 01 (one) month of passing such an order. The Disciplinary Committee and Vice Chancellor shall, as an appellate authority, review the case and pass such order as thought proper and just.</string>

    <string name="academicConsist1">The Academic year consists of:\n\n1. Tri-Semester (Four months semester) System and\n2. Bi-Semester (Six-months semester) System.</string>
    <string name="forTrisemster">For Tri-Semester System, there are three semesters in each academic year:\n\n1. Spring semester begins from 2nd  week of January and continues for four months;\n2. Summer semester begins from 2nd week of May and continues for four months;\n3. Fall Semester begins from 2nd week of September and continues for four months.</string>
    <string name="forBiSemester">For Bi-Semester System, there are two semesters in each academic year:\n\n1. Spring semester begins from January  and continues for Six months;\n2. Fall Semester begins from July and continues for Six months.</string>
    <string name="registraton1">Registration</string>
    <string name="regis2">Before the beginning of a semester (Spring/Summer/Fall), students have to register for courses in consultation with Heads of Departments/the departmental Coordinator. The students have to select the appropriate courses &amp; pay the required fees and register on SMS (Student Management System) for the semester.</string>
    <string name="regis3">Students may pre-register for the appropriate course at any time during an academic year. They may do so only in consultation with the Heads of Departments and the departmental coordinator concerned. </string>
    <string name="general1">General Rules of Registration</string>
    <string name="general2">\n1. A Registration is incomplete, until taka 500 is paid for semester registration or the student have dues from the previous semester.\n\n2. A student cannot register after the scheduled date of registration mentioned in the academic calendar except by special permission of the Dean of the concerned Faculty.\n\n3. Registration for a semester is conducted in accordance with an academic calendar. It starts immediately preceding the commencement of classes and continues up to the second week of classes.\n\n4. Transfer students are provided with the opportunity to register in advance on specific registration days meant for new students.\n\n5. Mere attendance does not constitute registration in a class.\n\n6. Changes of courses can only be made through the processing of an official registration form.\n\n7. The total fees for each semester can divided into two halves. A half shall have to be paid 15 days before the semester midterm examination and other half 15 days before the semester final examination. Total fees for each semester can also be paid in one installment in advance. A student will not be registered online until fees are paid according to the schedule given above and will not also get admit card for examination.\n\n8. Students may not drop a course merely by stopping attending classes.</string>
    <string name="readmission1">Readmission &amp; Re-registration</string>
    <string name="readmission2">A student who is in good academic standing, but who does not register in a full academic year (i.e.in three/two consecutive semesters respectively for tri-/bi- semester), will have to take re-admission paying readmission fee afresh, re-register all the courses &amp; attend classes accordingly with ongoing batch of students paying normal semester fees &amp; other dues, if any</string>
    <string name="internship1">Internship Requirement</string>
    <string name="internship2">students may be interned in organizations for three to six months, allowing two more weeks for writing reports, etc.  It is preferred that students applying for internship should have completed all the courses works. The Head of the department or Dean of the Faculty may authorize exceptions to these rules.</string>
    <string name="oriantation1">Orientation Program</string>
    <string name="oriantation2">Students are expected to participate in the orientation program which takes place at the beginning of the semester. The orientation program acquaints the students with rules, university policies, the educational opportunities, facilities and services and faculty members of the university.   </string>
    <string name="studentIdentifiaction1">Students Identification Cards</string>
    <string name="studentIdentifiaction2">All students will receive photo ID cards with their student numbers. The cards will be used for various purposes such as entering the university campus, attending classes, using the library and getting access to the computer/ internet lab.</string>
    <string name="degreeCom1">Degree Completion Deadline</string>
    <string name="degreeCom2">\n1. An Undergraduate degree program except Architecture must be completed within six {6} years time from the date of enrolment.\n\n2. An Undergraduate degree program in Architecture must be completed within seven {7} years time from the date of enrolment.\n\n3. A Graduate degree must be completed within four {4}Years time from the date of enrolment.\n\n4. Any exception to the above must be approved by the Academic Council of the university.</string>

    <string name="messageFromFounder">\n\nEurope and USA are the homes of about twenty percent of the world population. But they have been ruling the world for the last 400 years. This has been possible purely due to their technological superiority. Since World War-2, the world has been transformed into a global village with scientific inventions leading to economic and social revolutions. But all the modern inventions took place in the western world. The rest of the world has been following the leading western countries in all fields of science, technology, economy etc.\n\nWe are lagging behind due to lack of modern high-standard scientific education. We have institutions, but they are not manned or equipped with appropriate teachers, equipment, facilities and environment.\n\nEstablishments of private universities is a new phenomenon in Bangladesh. From 1992 to 2001 a total number of I7 private universities were allowed to enroll students. In 2002, another 37 private universities were granted permission to commence operations. This number will be increasing rapidly with the passage of time. The opening of the large number of private universities in quick succession created critical shortage of resources, especially good quality teachers, as required for modern higher education. As a result, the quality of education has suffered in Bangladesh in some cases. In a recent survey of universities throughout the world by Shanghai University shows that not a single university of this country could be included among the top 500 universities.\n\nEconomic development of erstwhile East Pakistan, the present Bangladesh, commenced in 1961. Development budget was prepared, administration was decentralized, new universities including Technical and Agricultural Universities were established, colleges were opened at sub-divisional and upazila levels, High schools were established at union levels, new industries sprang up, a network of high-ways were constructed, towns were modernized, medical colleges were opened, hospitals at upazila levels were constructed, malaria, cholera, tuberculosis and small pox were eradicated and private sector was encouraged by the government. After liberation in 1971, the administration was again centralized and a pragmatic economy was introduced in the interest of common people.\n\nIn the 80s, vigorous decentralization including Upazila Parishad, Zila Parishad and judiciary up to Upazila level was introduced. Privatization of commerce and industries was completed.\n\nDuring the last 3 decades, the latent talents of the people have been encouraged through privatization. New industries including garment, textile, leather, iron, chemicals and medicine have been established for domestic and export markets. People have become outward-looking and are going to far off counties for employment and business. The percentage of educated people has increased sharply. New ideas, plans and activities are noticed in all spheres of life. Dhaka has become a sprawling capital city. Many private universities were established by new entrepreneurs. Textile and Leather Institutes are churning out thousands of graduates every year who are working as catalysts for the economy. The development works of the last 44 years, have provided the nation with all types of necessary infrastructures. In spite of these spectacular developments, where do we stand now in the global context?\n\nWhen the world is working with robots, nanotechnology and hybrid engines, Bangladesh has been importing needles for garment industries. While developed countries have already completed gene mapping and currently conducting brain mapping, our Universities, Colleges and Research Institutions (BCSIR and Atomic Energy Commission) have no modern program and equipment. For innovation, the country needs well-educated workforce, financial backing, supportive government policies and co-operation of universities with industries in the field of technology.\n\nTo achieve the goal of modernization, the private universities, including teachers and management must have a grand vision and commitments. A modern road map to the future of the nation and next generation is required. Do we have that vision and the road map? Have we got that type of enlightened visionary and committed teachers and researches? It needs self-analysis and soul-searching. We can try our best in the present environment and with available resources to expand the horizon further.</string>

    <string name="vc_mezba">Prof. Dr. Mesbah Uddin Ahmed (Mesbah Kamal)\n\nUGC Post-doctoral fellowship (on-going),\n\nPh.D. Awarded from University of Dhaka,\n\nMA in History, University of Dhaka\n\nBA (H) in History, University of Dhaka\n\nVice Chancellor (Acting)\n\nEmail: vc@bu.edu.bd</string>
    <string name="vc_taif">Dr. Quazi Taif Sadat, PhD\n\nDirector\n\nEmail: taif@panbangla.com</string>
    <string name="vc_shamima">Shamima Khan\n\nExecutive (Ps to VC)\n\nEmail: shamimakhan27@gmail.com\n\nPhone: 01755559329</string>

    <!--    name of broad of trust-->
    <string name="bot_jamil">Jamil Azher/n/nChairman, BoT, BU</string>
    <string name="bot_Ghulam">M.A. Ghulam Dastagir\n\nSecretary, BoT, BU</string>
    <string name="bot_tarapada">Tarapada Biswas</string>
    <string name="bot_masih">Engr. Masih ur Rahman</string>
    <string name="bot_mozahar">Quazi Mozaher Ali</string>
    <string name="bot_wahiuddin">Dr. Wahiuddin Mahmood</string>
    <string name="bot_shagufta">Dr. Shagufta Mahmood</string>
    <string name="bot_shahlina">Shahnila Tazreen Azher</string>
    <string name="bot_ansari">Shihab Ansari Azher</string>
    <string name="bot_musfiqur">Engr. Mushfiqur Rahman</string>
    <string name="bot_sadia">Barrister Sadia Malik</string>
    <string name="bot_iqbal">Ar. Iqbal Habib</string>
    <string name="bot_sharmin">Advocate Sarmin Ahmed Mazumder</string>

    <!--    name of registrar-->
    <string name="rBrig">Brig. Gen. Md. Mahbubul Haque (Retd)\nRegistrar|n\nEmail: registrar.bu@bu.edu.bd\nPhone: 02 8117951\nFax: +88 02 9141019</string>
    <string name="rSiddiqur">Md. Siddiqur Rahman\nDeputy Registrar\n\nEmail: deputyregistrar.le@bu.edu.bd\nPhone: 01755559324,\n01771186003</string>
    <string name="rNaureen">Naureen Ayesha\nDeputy Registrar\nEmail: deputyregistrar@bu.edu.bd\nPhone: 01755511980</string>
    <string name="rMosiur" tools:ignore="Typos">Md. Moshiur Rahman\nSenior Assistant Registrar\nEmail: sr.asst.registrar1@bu.edu.bd\nPhone: 01755511976</string>
    <string name="rMorshedul">Md. Morshedul Alam\nSenior Assistant Registrar\nEmail: sr.asst.registrar2@bu.edu.bd\nPhone: 01755556547</string>
    <string name="rUrfa" tools:ignore="Typos">Urfa Zewar\nAssistant Registrar\nEmail: asst.registrar1@bu.edu.bd\nPhone: 01755511974</string>
    <string name="rShafiquzzam">Mohammad Shafiquzzaman\nCoordinator, Office of the Chairman\nEmail: shafiq.orion@gmail.com\nPhone: 01755559322</string>
    <string name="rTariqul">Md. Tariqul Islam\nProcurement Officer\nEmail: procurement@bu.edu.bd</string>
    <string name="rMunim">S. M. Munim Rahman\nAssistant Engineer (Civil)\nEmail: asst.engr.civil@bu.edu.bd\nPhone: 01957545628</string>
    <string name="rProvakor">Provakar Roy\nIT Executive\nEmail: it@bu.edu.bd\nPhone: 01755511983</string>
    <string name="rNigram">Md Nigran Islam Mizan\nIT Executive (Web Develop)\nEmail: it@bu.edu.bd\nPhone: 01755511984</string>
    <string name="rSaniyul">Md. Saniyal Haque Khan\nExecutive (Academic Affairs)\nEmail: jisan.saniyal@gmail.com\nPhone: 01717236398</string>
    <string name="rRofiqul">Md. Rofikul Islam\nExecutive (PA to Registrar)\nEmail: rafique3657@gmail.com\nPhone: 01715636654</string>
    <string name="rNurUddin">Nur Uddin\nJr. Asst. Engineer (Electrical)\nEmail: nuruddinrocky02@gmail.com\nPhone: 01310550265</string>
    <string name="rnadira">Nadira Akter\nAssistant Course Coordinator\nEmail: naktercse@gmail.com\nPhone: 01755556548</string>
    <string name="rhatem">Md. Hatem Ali\nAssistant: Reg. Office	Email: registrar@bu.edu.bd,\nhatembu@gmail.com\nPhone: 01755511978</string>
    <string name="rJapor">Md. Jafor Ali\nOffice Assistant\nEmail: zaforiqbal291@gmail.com\nPhone: 01736232168</string>
    <string name="rKhandakar">Khandakar Shahadat Hossain\nOffice Assistant\nEmail: registrar@bu.edu.bd,\nkh.shahadathossain@outlook.com\nPhone: 01728474953</string>
    <string name="rFarzana">Farjana Ahmed\nDeputy Registrar\nEmail: dr.admission@bu.edu.bd\nPhone: 01755559325</string>
    <string name="rAbdullah">Md. Abdullah Al Mamun\nAssistant Admission Officer\nEmail: admission@bu.edu.bd,\nmdabdullahalmamun709@gmail.com\nPhone: 01755559320</string>
    <string name="rJannat">Jannat Bhuyan\nAssistant Admission Officer\nEmail: admission@bu.edu.bd,\nbhuiyanjannat@gmail.com\nPhone: 01755559301</string>
    <string name="rTariqulIslam">Md. Tariqul Islam\nSenior Assistant Registrar (HR)	Email: hr@bu.edu.bd,\ntislam83@yahoo.com\nPhone: 01755559309</string>
    <string name="rDebasis">Debasis Roy\nHR Executive\nEmail: hr@bu.edu.bd,\naarovroydev@gmail.com\nPhone: 01313034731</string>
    <string name="rAbubakkar">Md. Abu Bakar Siddik\nOffice Assistant (HR)\nEmail: absiddik0110@gmail.com\nPhone: 01755677923</string>
    <string name="rShohel">Md. Shohel Ahsan Nipu\nDeputy Registrar\nEmail: pr@bu.edu.bd\nPhone: 01755559310\nFax: +88 02 9141019</string>
    <string name="rHedayat">Md. Hedayet Ali Biswas\nExecutive (Lab Admin)\nEmail: hedayetcse@gmail.com\nPhone: 01733620273</string>
    <string name="rAlamgir">Md. Alamgir Hossain\nOffice Assistant (Dean, SET)\nEmail: alamgirhossain927@gmail.com\nPhone: 01952297880</string>
    <string name="rShorab">Md. Sohrab Hossain\nOffice Assistant (BBA)\nEmail: hossainsohrab92@gmail.com\nPhone: 01681135680</string>
    <string name="rKhan">Khan Mohammad Sheartaj\nOffice Assistant\nEmail: shafatkhan1010@gmail.com\nPhone: 01795075306</string>
    <string name="rjahangir">Md. Jahangir Alam\nOffice Assistant (English &amp; Eco and Math)\nEmail: jahangir.bsc6@gmail.com\nPhone: 01558305123</string>
    <string name="rAminul">Aminul Islam\nOffice Assistant (Law &amp; Sociology)\nEmail: rubelkhanbd6@gmail.com\nPhone: 01641311117</string>
    <string name="rImran">Md. Imran Hasan\nLab Assistant (Pharmacy)\nEmail: imranhasan_2017@yahoo.com\nPhone: 0174689793</string>
    <string name="rOhidul">Md. Ohidul Islam\nLab Assistant (Pharmacy)\nEmail: anikbu@gmail.com\nPhone:  01912943419</string>
    <string name="rAbdul">Md. Abdul Alim\nLab Assistant (CSE)\nEmail: smalimsarkar820@gmail.com\nPhone: 01758616066</string>
    <string name="rFazlul">Md. Fazlul Haque Siddique\nComputer Lab Assistant cum Library in-charge (Architecture)\nEmail: siddique0dkh@gmail.com\nPhone: 01782178879</string>
    <string name="rMoin">Md. Moin Uddin Niloy\nLab Assistant (EEE)\nEmail: niloykhan74@gmail.com\nPhone: 01303118552</string>
    <string name="rSabuj" tools:ignore="Typos">Md. Sabuj Rana\nLab Assistant (Pharmacy)\nEmail: md.sabujranadgc1@gmail.com\nPhone: 01785392642</string>

    <!--    controller-->
    <string name="ramirul">Prof. Md. Amirul Alam Khan\nEmail: controller@bu.edu.bd</string>
    <string name="rDidar">Didar Elahi\nEmail: deputycontroller@bu.edu.bd\nPhone: 01755511988</string>
    <string name="rrajib" tools:ignore="Typos">Md. Rajib Hossain\nEmail: asst.controller1@bu.edu.bd\nPhone: 01755511975</string>
    <string name="rnaeem">Md. Naeem Ahammed\nEmail: asst.controller2@bu.edu.bd\nPhone: 01755677927</string>
    <string name="rMoniruzzam">Moniruzaman Biswas\nOffice Assistant\nEmail: sabujbiswas006@gmail.com\nPhone: 01716481419</string>
    <string name="rliza">Liza Moni\nOffice Assistant\nEmail: lizamoni@yahoo.com\nPhone:  01740243896</string>
    <string name="rsushanto">Shusanto Kumar Das\nOffice Assistant\nEmail: santosabuj@gmail.com\nPhone: 01739854019</string>

    <!--    accounts-->
    <string name="aakther">Akther Hossain\nDeputy Director\nAccounts &amp; Finance and Audit\nEmail: dd.f.a@bu.edu.bd\nPhone: 01755559306</string>
    <string name="asheak">Sheakh Farid Hossain\nJr. Assistant Director (A &amp; F)\nEmail: accounts@bu.edu.bd,\nsheakhfarid@yahoo.com\nPhone: 01915679309</string>
    <string name="asamad">A. Samad Molla\nJr. Assistant Director (A &amp; F)\nEmail: accounts@bu.edu.bd,\nasamadmolla_narail@yahoo.com\nPhone: 01712845955</string>
    <string name="ashamima">Shamima Akter\nJr. Assistant Director (A &amp; F)	Email: shamima.ak1130@gmail.com\nPhone: 01755677926</string>
    <string name="amushfequr">Shaikh Mushfequr Rahman\nOffice Assistant\nEmail: sk.mushfequr@gmail.com\nPhone: 01865550008</string>
    <string name="aabdullah">Abdullah- Al-Mahmud\nOffice Assistant\nEmail: almahmud.bu@gmail.com\nPhone: 01927365592</string>

    <!--    library-->
    <string name="lnawsin">Nawshin Laila\nSr. Assistant Librarian (Main Campus)\nEmail: librarian@bu.edu.bd\nPhone: +88 02 8117951 (Ext- 121)</string>
    <string name="lmojlesur">Md. Mokhlasur Rahman\nJr. Assistant Librarian (Main Campus)\nEmail: m.mokhlasur_selimreaza@yahoo.com\nPhone: 01789539500</string>
    <string name="lmahabul">Md. Mahabul Islam\nJr. Asst. Librarian\nEmail: mmahabul2020@gmail.com\nPhone: 01862785825</string>
    <string name="lsima">Sima Rani Bhowmick\nCataloguer (Main Campus)\nEmail: simarani_du@yahoo.com\nPhone: 01746430971</string>
    <string name="abdulAlim">Md. Abdul Alim\nCataloguer (2nd Campus)\nEmail: abdulalim_ismc@yahoo.com\nPhone: 01986028407</string>

    <!--    IT-->
    <string name="ikhabir">Md. Khabir Uddin\nSenior Software Architect\nSoftware Consultant (Part-time)\nEmail: khabir.uddin@bu.edu.bd</string>
    <string name="iataur">Md. Ataur Rahman\nSoftware Consultant\nEmail: ataur_rahman@onirban.net</string>
    <string name="imehedi">Md. Mahedi Mahfuj\nSoftware Consultant (Part-time)\nEmail: md.mahedimahfuj@gmail.com</string>
    <string name="iprovakor">Provakar Roy\nIT Executive\nEmail: it@bu.edu.bd\nPhone: 01755511983</string>
    <string name="inigram">Md Nigran Islam Mizan\nIT Executive (Web Develop)\nEmail: it@bu.edu.bd\nPhone: 01755511984</string>

    <!--    cse section front-->
    <string name="cseAdvisor">Quazi Jamil Azher\n\nAdvisor\n\nDepartment of CSE</string>
    <string name="cseFromHead">Md. Sadiq Iqbal\n\nAssistant Professor &amp; Head\n\nDepartment of CSE</string>

    <!--    listOfCSEFacultymembers-->
    <string name="fSadiq">Md. Sadiq Iqbal\nFaculty Id :200510001\nDesignation :Associate Professor &amp; Chairman</string>
    <string name="fAsraf">Dr. Md. Asraf Ali\nFaculty Id :200510038\nDesignation :Associate Professor</string>
    <string name="fYasir">Yeasir Fathah Rumi\nFaculty Id :200510003\nDesignation :Assistant Professor &amp; Department Coordinator</string>
    <string name="fSahriar">A.H.M Shahariar Parvez\nFaculty Id :200710004\nDesignation :Assistant Professor</string>
    <string name="fIbrahim">Mohammed Ibrahim Hussain\nFaculty Id :200710005\nDesignation :Assistant Professor &amp; Semester program Coordinator</string>
    <string name="fRokeya">Mst. Rokeya Khatun\nFaculty Id :201210014\nDesignation :Assistant Professor</string>
    <string name="fSalma">Umme Salma\nFaculty Id :201310018\nDesignation :Senior Lecturer &amp; Coordinator</string>
    <string name="fArifin">Mohammad Arifin Rahman KHAN\nFaculty Id :201310019\nDesignation :Senior Lecturer</string>
    <string name="fAsraful">Ashraful Kabir Anik\nFaculty Id :201310021\nDesignation :Lecturer</string>
    <string name="fSadia">Sadia Afrin Shampa\nFaculty Id :201510032\nDesignation :Senior Lecturer</string>
    <string name="fjakir">Md Zakir Hossain\nFaculty Id :\nDesignation :Lecuturer</string>
    <string name="fTarique">Tarique Latif\nFaculty Id :201610049\nDesignation :Lecturer</string>
    <string name="fSaydur">Mohammad Sayeedur Rahman\nFaculty Id :201610051\nDesignation :Lecturer</string>
    <string name="fRiaz">Md. Riaz Uddin\nFaculty Id :201710056\nDesignation :Lecturer</string>
    <string name="fMahfuz">Md. Mahfuj Howlader\nFaculty Id :201710057\nDesignation :Lecturer</string>
    <string name="fJubayer">Jubayer Al Mahmud\nFaculty Id :201710059\nDesignation :Lecturer</string>
    <string name="fSisir">Shishir Mallick\nFaculty Id :201810060\nDesignation :Lecturer</string>
    <string name="fTariqul">Md. Tariqul Islam\nFaculty Id :201810061\nDesignation :Lecturer</string>
    <string name="fHasib">Khan Md. Hasib\nFaculty Id :201810064\nDesignation :Lecturer &amp; Coordinator</string>
    <string name="fIftekharul">Md. Iftekharul Islam\nFaculty Id :201910067\nDesignation :Lecturer</string>
    <string name="fAfsana">Afsana Islam\nFaculty Id :201910068\nDesignation :Lecturer</string>
    <string name="fNazim">Nazim Uddin\nFaculty Id :201910069\nDesignation :Lecturer</string>
    <string name="fAhammad">Md. Abu Ahammed Babu\nFaculty Id :201910071\nDesignation :Lecturer</string>
    <string name="fShakil">Md Shakil Ahmed\nFaculty Id :201910072\nDesignation :Lecturer</string>
    <string name="fFazle">Fazle Rahat\nFaculty Id :202010073\nDesignation :Lecturer</string>
    <string name="fAhsan">Md. Ahsan Habib\nFaculty Id :202010074\nDesignation :Lecturer</string>
    <string name="fAnik">Anik Das\nFaculty Id :202010075\nDesignation :Lecturer</string>
    <string name="fAsib">Asib Hasan\nFaculty Id :202010076\nDesignation :Lecturer (Part-time)</string>

    <!--    link-->
    <string name="student_portal">https://busmsportal.azurewebsites.net/LoginPage.aspx</string>
    <string name="lab_facility_url">https://bu.edu.bd/lab-facility/</string>
    <string name="library_url">https://bu.edu.bd/library/</string>
    <string name="research_url">https://bu.edu.bd/research/</string>
    <string name="digital_education_url">https://bu.edu.bd/digital-education/</string>
    <string name="co_curricular_url">https://bu.edu.bd/co-curricular/</string>

    <string name="messageFromMathDepartmentHead">I am welcoming you all as the Head of the Department and this is a great pleasure to introduce the Department of Mathematics of Bangladesh University.\n\nI hope this website will provide you all the  information that you are looking for. \n\nBangladesh University started its journey in 2001 but University Grant Commission (UGC) approved the curriculum of the Bachelor of Science (Honours) in Mathematics in 2005. Department of Mathematics offers 4 years B.Sc. program in Mathematics.\n\nThe Mathematics curriculum highlights logical inference, with a focus on proving theorems and a view toward depth and obstruction. This course expose the depth and beauty of Mathematics as well as its applications to problems. This will also equip student with a solid and strong base in Mathematics.\n\nWe look forward  to  having you join us on this adventure.\n\n</string>
    <string name="messageFromPharmacyDepartmentHead">Welcome to the website of the Department of Pharmacy of the Bangladesh University. The Department started its journey from June 2004. The aim of the Pharmacy program in Bangladesh University is to prepare students to be the most skilled, responsible, and caring Pharmacist. Pharmacy is the profession responsible for the appropriate use of medications, devices and services in order to achieve optimal therapeutic outcomes. Pharmacy is a dynamic and fast growing profession in Bangladesh. Because of its contribution to our health-care system, Pharmacy has always been a high choice to the students coming for university education.</string>
    <string name="messageFromEEEDepartmentHead">Welcome to the department of Electrical and Electronic Engineering (EEE) at Bangladesh University. The department of EEE started its journey in March 2006. We have been able to establish ourselves as one of the leading EEE departments in the country within the last few years. Currently, we are situated at the Asad gate Building of the university and will soon head to the permanent campus at Adabor. The B.Sc. program is UGC approved and we are in progress for the IEB accreditation.\n\nOur faculty is committed to providing our students with opportunities for knowledge concentration and specialization to build healthy and sustainable communities. The Architecture Department emphasizes design education through diverse experiences which include learning through making, collaborative research, and community engagement.</string>
    <string name="messgaeofArchDept">We are at a significant moment in time for careers in architecture and the design of built environments. As architects and designers, we have a responsibility to think globally, and use our gifts and abilities respectfully.\n\nOur faculty is committed to providing our students with opportunities for knowledge concentration and specialization to build healthy and sustainable communities. The Architecture Department emphasizes design education through diverse experiences which include learning through making, collaborative research, and community engagement.\n\nOur students in the Bachelor of Architecture (B.Arch) can chart multiple professional paths grounded in a cross-disciplinary degree. The students become an architect after passing successfully 5 years course and gained experience practically and theoretically before graduation.</string>
    <string name="messageOfEnglish">English is the premiere language in higher education in our country as well as many other countries of the world. Careers in different sectors including high ranking governmental positions, science and technology require good command over English. It is also a pre-requisite for the students who aspire for higher studies overseas.\n\nKeeping this global importance in mind, our BA (Hons) and MA programs are designed to develop students’ linguistic capability through the teaching of both language and literature. Being familiar with great literature and writing, the learners will also be able to appreciate how human beings from different cultures and times have used literary arts to shape experiences thoughtfully and meaningfully.</string>
    <string name="messageOfSocilogy">On behalf of the Department of Sociology I would like to welcome to our departmental webpage. This department runs since 5th June, 2005 for achieving goals of Bangladesh University. The Department of sociology of Bangladesh University has the potential to become not only the leading sociology department in the country, but also in south Asia. It focuses on a complete education by training the students beyond the skills needed to perform in the job market. Sociology related education seeks to create a socially responsible person, endowing the student with the knowledge necessary to go about in the world. It allows one to know one’s culture, society and civilization as it enriches the soul and enhances humanity through the learning of the arts, history, music, literature, science, and philosophy.</string>
    <string name="messageOfLaw">Lawyers are Social Engineers as lawyering for the poor is lawyering for justice. With a vision to build the society, Bangladesh University (BU) has initiated the journey to impart Quality Legal Education within a very reasonable and moderate Tuition Fee, obviously within the affording capacity of the students of middle and lower middle class families of this country.I am delighted to be a part of this noble venture.\n\nProf. Dr. Md. Nazmuzzaman Bhuian from the Department of Law of the University of Dhaka has adorned the post of the honorable Advisor of this Department; it’s an achievement for the Department of Law of BU.\n\nThe Department is enriched with a set of young, energetic and enthusiastic full time and adjunct faculty members with full devotion and sincerity with a proven track record of academic excellence from home and abroad. With the guidance of such able academics, students of this Department have already qualified themselves in Advocate ship Enrolment, Judiciary and in various other corporate private jobs. A few of them have also obtained fully funded foreign scholarships.\n\nWe have an updated syllabus duly approved by the UGC for the 4 Years LL.B. (Hones) Program, LL.M. 1 year and 2 Years Program.We have a permanent Moot Court Room which may be treated as the heart of this Department.The students can master the skills and tactics of lawyering as a dynamic, smart, thrilling and noble profession in real sense. As a part of this skill development initiatives, Department arranges Court Visit Program with the students regularly once in a semester so that the students may learn the Court Proceedings practically.Besides, the Department frequently arranges Seminars, Workshops, Certificate Training Courses on various contemporary national and international legal and human rights issues.</string>
    <string name="messageOfEconomics">Economics as a branch of human knowledge has been enriching itself in both depth and spread in the contemporary world. Complex modern life more and more resorts primarily to Economics to deal with questions like development and equity, ethics and moral, politics and culture, both in micro and macro levels. Down to earth issues like growth, inequality, poverty, health, pollution etc. are progressively emerging as core contents of the discipline. Excellence in higher education in economics constitutes therefore the vital ingredient of the nation building task. Department of Economics of Bangladesh University invites young dreamers to join the brigade of future nation builders who are being groomed here with utmost care and professionalism.</string>
    <string name="messageOfBA">Department of Business Administration (DBA) is the largest and leading Department of Bangladesh University in respect of quality and quantity. Bachelor of Business Administration (BBA) and Masters of Business Administration (MBA) are two prestigious programs of DBA of this university. DBA offers these two legendary programs to develop future business leaders and skilled managerial resources for the country in order to cope up with the present and future needs of a developing country like ours. DBA provides education in both traditional and emerging subjects in business and management, ranging from Accounting, Finance, Human Resource Management and Marketing. The course(s) curriculum of DBA has been designed and developed in such a way so that the students of this Department can effectively discharge their duties and responsibilities in different positions from the mid level to top level administration as well as can face the challenges of the 21st century’s globalized world business. At present, a huge number of BBA &amp; MBA Degree holders are serving different positions of corporate, Government and multinational organizations, both at home and abroad. Apart from different academic activities, the Department of Business Administration takes the initiative of different skill-enhancing extra-curricular activities.</string>
</resources>
